facultyfocus.com 2019-04-04

# Privacy Policy - Faculty Focus | Higher Ed Teaching & Learning

## FacultyFocus.com is a website of Magna Publications Madison, WI 53704

This website is owned and operated by Magna Publications.  We are committed to protecting the privacy of our visitors while they interact with the content, products, and services on this site (the “Site”).  This Privacy Policy applies to the Site only. It does not apply to other websites to which we link.  Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we want you to understand what information we collect about you, how we collect it, how that information is used, and how you can control our disclosure of it. You agree that your use of the Site signifies your assent to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Site.

**1)   Information Collected**

We collect two types of information from you: i) information that you voluntarily provide to us (e.g. through a voluntary registration process, sign-ups or emails); and ii) information that is derived through automated tracking mechanisms.

  * Voluntary Registration Information.

In order to fully access this Site, you must first complete the registration process, during which we will collect personal information about you. The information will include your name, title, institution, address, phone number, and email address. We do not collect personally identifiable information about you except when you specifically provide such information to us on a voluntary basis.

By registering with us, you consent to the use and method of disclosure as described in this Privacy Policy.

  * Voluntary Information for Services and Features

We [also] collect personally identifiable information when you choose to use certain other features of the Site, including: i) making purchases, ii) consenting to receive email or text messages about upcoming promotions or events, iii) consenting to receive email, iv) participating in our forum, iv) commenting on articles, v) accessing articles and on-demand programs. When you choose to use these additional features, we require you to provide your “Contact Information” in addition to other personal information that may be required to complete a transaction such as your phone number, billing and shipping addresses and credit card information.  Occasionally, we may also request information such as your shopping preferences and demographics which will help us better serve you and our others users in the future.

  *  Cookies

Our site uses “cookies” and other tracking technologies.  Cookies enable us to serve secure pages to our users without asking them to sign in repeatedly.  Most browsers allow you to control cookies, including whether or not to accept them and how to remove them. If a user’s system is idle for a defined time, the cookie will expire, forcing the user to sign in again to continue their session. This prevents unauthorized access to the user’s information while they are away from their computer.

You may set most browsers to notify you if you receive a cookie, or you may choose to block cookies with your browser, but please note that if you choose to erase or block your cookies, you will need to re-enter your original user ID and password to gain access to certain parts of the Site.

Third-Party Cookies:  In the course of serving advertisements to this site, our third-party advertisers may place or recognize a unique “cookie” on your browser.

**2)   How We Use Your Information**

Magna Publications will not disclose, give, or sell any email address information to third parties for any purposes other than to our suppliers and other third parties who need to know in order to deliver services on behalf of Magna Publications or unless required to do so by law. Further, Magna Publications reserves the right to contact you regarding matters relevant to the underlying service provided and/or the information collected.

You may receive print mailings from Magna Publications or other reputable companies, however you can have your name put on our do-not-share list by calling us at the number provided above, e-mailing us at the above address, writing to us at the above address. Again, as an overall policy, we do not sell or share email addresses of our customers with any third parties. To be removed from any of our promotional lists, please provide us with your exact name and address

Please note that personally identifiable information is used only to provide you with a more enjoyable, convenient online experience and to help us identify and/or provide information, products, or services that may be of interest to you. We use your personally identifiable information to support and enhance your use of the Site and its features, including without limitation: fulfilling your order; providing customer service; tracking usage of subscriptions; and otherwise supporting your use of the Site.

Magna Publications may use your personal information for target advertising toward you based on things such as region, products purchased, job responsibilities, etc.

We may permit certain trusted third parties to track usage, analyze data such as the source address that a page request is coming from, your IP address or domain name, the date and time of the page request, the referring Web site (if any) and other parameters in the URL. This is collected in order to better understand our Web site usage, and enhance the performance of services to maintain and operate the Site and certain features on the Site. We may use third parties to host the Site; operate various features available on the Site; send emails; analyze data; provide search results and links and assist in fulfilling your orders.

WE ARE NOT LIABLE OR RESPONSIBLE FOR THE PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE OR OTHER INFORMATION YOU CHOOSE TO SUBMIT IN FORUMS SUCH AS A BULLETIN BOARD, CHAT ROOM OR ANY OTHER PUBLICLY ACCESSIBLE AREA OF THE SITE.

**3) How We Protect Your Information**

We are committed to protecting the information we receive from you. We take appropriate security measures to protect your information against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we maintain appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information and data stored on our system. While no computer system is completely secure, we believe the measures we have implemented reduce the likelihood of security problems to a level appropriate to the type of data involved.

**4) Third Party Advertising**

Advertisements appearing on this Site may be delivered to you by Magna Publications or one of our Web advertising partners. Our Web advertising partners may set cookies. Doing this allows the advertising partners to recognize your computer each time they send you an advertisement. In this way, they may compile information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisements and determine which advertisements are clicked. This information allows an advertising partner to deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. Magna Publications does not have access to or control of the cookies that may be placed by the third party advertising servers of ad partners.

This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by Magna Publications on magnapubs.comand does not cover the use of cookies by any of its advertisers.

**5)   Accessing and Updating Your Personal Information and Preferences**

We provide mechanisms for updating and correcting your personal information for many of our services.  You may modify or remove any of your personal information at any time by logging into your account and accessing features such as edit and account.

**6) Email Choice/Opt-out**

If any user who receives an email from the Magna Publication and would prefer not to receive such communications in the future, [he or she] can do so by following the instructions at the bottom of the emails. If you prefer, you may call us at 800-433-0499 during business hours or send an email to support@magnapubs.com. We will implement your opt-out requests promptly, but you may still receive communications from us for up to ten business days as we process your request.

**7) Children’s Privacy and Parental Controls**

We do not solicit any personal information from children. If you are not 18 or older, you are not authorized to use the Site. Parents should be aware that there are parental control tools available online that can be used to prevent children from submitting information online without parental permission or from accessing material that is harmful to minors.

**8) Disclaimer to Security**

By consenting to the Terms and Conditions of the Site and hence the Privacy Policy, you consent that no data transmission over the Internet is completely secure. We cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you provide to us and you transmit such information to us at your own risk.

**9) Notification of Changes**

Magna Publications reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy from time to time at its sole discretion. If at some point in the future, there is a change to our Privacy Policy, unless we obtain your express consent, such change will only apply to information collected after the revised Privacy Policy took effect. Your continued use of the Site indicates your assent to the Privacy Policy as posted.

**10)   CONTACT INFORMATION:**

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy please contact:

Magna Publications Customer Support 2718 Dryden Drive Madison, Wisconsin, 53704 800-433-0499 support@magnapubs.com [www.magnapubs.com](http://www.magnapubs.com/)
